<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>KI - Our Updates</title>
    <link>https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights</link>
    <description>Get the latest updates and investment insights from the Kiwi Invest team. Find out answers to key questions, get an understanding of what’s going on in the markets and get the low down with opinion pieces written by our expert investment management team.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 03:34:49 GMT</pubDate>
    <dc:date>2020-12-07T03:34:49Z</dc:date>
    <dc:language>en</dc:language>
    <item>
      <title>Investment Update November 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/market-update-november</link>
      <description>&lt;div class="hs-featured-image-wrapper"&gt; 
 &lt;a href="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/market-update-november" title="" class="hs-featured-image-link"&gt; &lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hubfs/Kiwi%20Investment%20Management/Monthly%20update%20%28Missive%29/GlobalMarketUpdate-NOVDEC-1200px.png" alt="Investment Update November 2020" class="hs-featured-image" style="width:auto !important; max-width:50%; float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;"&gt; &lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;    
&lt;h2&gt;Global Market View&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;November was a great month for stock markets (though not the NZ bond market!), in particular for more economically sensitive areas of the US stock market “value” stocks. The rotation from growth to value stocks benefited shares of companies that are likely to gain in value from an Investment Update December 2020 economic recovery as opposed to those that benefited from the stay-at-home trend. Energy stocks were up markedly with higher oil prices. Financials, industrials and materials also rose. This saw the Dow Jones Industrials Index surge to all-time highs crossing the 30,000 level for the first time in history before finishing the month slightly below this peak (but still recording an 11.8% gain for its best monthly performance since January 1987). The Eurozone, UK, Asia and Japan also saw significant increases in their respective indices as global equities enjoyed a purple patch.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;Global Market View&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;November was a great month for stock markets (though not the NZ bond market!), in particular for more economically sensitive areas of the US stock market “value” stocks. The rotation from growth to value stocks benefited shares of companies that are likely to gain in value from an Investment Update December 2020 economic recovery as opposed to those that benefited from the stay-at-home trend. Energy stocks were up markedly with higher oil prices. Financials, industrials and materials also rose. This saw the Dow Jones Industrials Index surge to all-time highs crossing the 30,000 level for the first time in history before finishing the month slightly below this peak (but still recording an 11.8% gain for its best monthly performance since January 1987). The Eurozone, UK, Asia and Japan also saw significant increases in their respective indices as global equities enjoyed a purple patch.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;The major catalyst driving the value rotation has been the incredibly positive vaccine news that was released in November, with 3 different potential vaccines releasing results, and efficacy numbers as high as 95%. In turn, this positive data helped alleviate fears that society will have to learn to live with the virus on a more permanent basis and offers the hope of a much quicker return to normal than had been anticipated only a month ago. That said, many countries will continue to be ravaged by COVID-19 through the Northern Hemisphere winter but there is now real hope of a way forward. The other major&lt;br&gt;catalyst behind the moves was the US election, where, while it took a bit longer than normal to get a final result, the heavily contested scenario that had been a source of concern for investors didn’t arise, with the General Services Administration having now moved to begin the formal transition process to President-Elect Biden.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;The shock financial markets news in New Zealand in November was the public faceoff between the Minister of Finance and the Governor of the RBNZ over the RBNZ’s perceived role (via accommodative monetary policy) in fuelling the current housing market frenzy. The public nature of the discussions certainly spurred market participants into action as the probability of the OCR turning negative was taken off the table. This saw the yield on the 10-year NZ government bond increase by 32 bps for the month.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Offshore, Government bond yields were also volatile during the month. The US 10-year Treasury yield was 3 bps lower at 0.84%, but saw large daily changes around the US election and news on vaccines. Corporate bonds performed well, with global investment grade producing a total return of 2.1% and high yield 4.1% (Source: ICE BofAML, local currency total returns).&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hs-fs/hubfs/Kiwi%20Investment%20Management/Monthly%20update%20(Missive)/GlobalMarketUpdate-NOVDEC-1200px.png?width=796&amp;amp;name=GlobalMarketUpdate-NOVDEC-1200px.png" alt="GlobalMarketUpdate-NOVDEC-1200px" width="796" style="background-color: transparent; width: 796px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="#growth-performance"&gt;Growth Performance&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; |&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="#growth-positioning"&gt;Growth Positioning&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; |&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="#fixed-interest-performance"&gt;Fixed Interest Performance&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; |&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="#fixed-interest-positioning"&gt;Fixed Interest Positioning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;h2&gt;Growth&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hs-fs/hubfs/nathan-field.png?width=90&amp;amp;name=nathan-field.png" alt="nathan-field" width="90" style="background-color: transparent; width: 90px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hs-fs/hubfs/Steffan-3.png?width=90&amp;amp;name=Steffan-3.png" alt="Steffan-3" width="90" style="background-color: transparent; width: 90px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;by Nathan Field, Portfolio Manager - Global Thematic and Steffan Berridge, Head of Quantitative Strategy&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;h3&gt;Performance&lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;The Kiwi Wealth Growth Fund (Growth PIE) returned 5.82% after tax and fees in November, 2.28% behind the MSCI All Country benchmark which returned 8.09%. The Quantitative and Thematic equity strategies contributed negatively to relative performance this month, but Core Global provided some upside. In addition, the alternative assets outperformed cash, but underperformed equities. The Kiwi dollar strengthened against the US greenback last month, which was a headwind for foreign currency returns.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Global Thematic produced positive returns but lagged the surge in global equities in November. Our bias towards quality companies that served us well through the first ten months on 2020 quickly became a headwind when the vaccine news broke, as investors flocked back to cyclical industries like energy, airlines, and metals and mining. The vaccine-fuelled rotation meant that our worst performers were defensive stocks like &lt;strong&gt;Pepsi&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Nestle&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Procter &amp;amp; Gamble&lt;/strong&gt; – all of which remain important longterm holdings, but a risk-hungry environment will see these names struggle to keep up. While our strategy might have lagged the benchmark in November, we are still sitting on healthy year-to-date outperformance, effectively smoothing the ride for investors.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;The Global Quantitative fund underpreformed as breakthrough vaccine results provided a massive boost to down-and-out segments of the market. The Pfizer/BioNTech announcement on 9 November that preliminary trial results showed 90% effectiveness took the market by surprise and led to the biggest daily momentum crash and junk rally on record. The biggest sector beneficiary of the announcement was Energy, which spiked 12% higher on the day as the market priced in a 2021 demand rebound.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Our lag to benchmark was evident across a number of sectors where the lockdown/recovery theme was at play and had created a wide junk/quality split matching the K-shaped recovery narrative. Our worst sectors were Financials and Technology where our underweight to Banks (&lt;strong&gt;JP Morgan&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Citigroup&lt;/strong&gt;) and focus on Tech businesses that were proving robust to lockdown conditions (&lt;strong&gt;NortonLifeLock&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Nintendo&lt;/strong&gt;) suffered relative to benchmark. Our best sectors were underweights in Real Estate and Utilities, and our best position was Macy’s, which ripped 42% higher for the month.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;h3&gt;Positioning&lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;In Global Thematic, the positive vaccine news has prompted us to alter our positioning in Global Thematic, and we have added to bombed-out travel-related stocks (&lt;strong&gt;Boeing&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Marriot Hotels&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Hyatt Hotels&lt;/strong&gt;) in anticipation of a rebound in leisure travel spending. The recent rise in US rates and steepening of the yield curve has also led to an increase in our financials exposure.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;For Global Quantitative, our top-down positioning targets higher quality companies and sectors seen as more suited to the current environment. Stock selection favours companies with attractive metrics across earnings quality, capital efficiency, valuations, sentiment and sustainability. Over the month, we reduced our underweights in Financials and Energy (Bank of Montreal, EOG Resources), and reduced allocation to Staples (&lt;strong&gt;Church &amp;amp; Dwight&lt;/strong&gt;) and Discretionary (&lt;strong&gt;Alibaba&lt;/strong&gt;). Technology, Industrials and Materials are our favoured sectors while Energy and Utilities are our largest underweights.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;h2&gt;Fixed Interest&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hs-fs/hubfs/images/team/blog-authors/diana-g-125px.png?width=90&amp;amp;name=diana-g-125px.png" alt="diana-g-125px" width="90" style="width: 90px; float: left; margin: 0px 10px 10px 0px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;by Diana Gordon, Head of Fixed Interest&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;h3&gt;Performance&lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;The Kiwi Wealth Fixed Interest Fund (Fixed Interest PIE) returned -0.81% after fees and taxes in November outperforming its benchmark which returned -1.32%. The outperformance can largely be attributed to having lower maturity bonds than the benchmark at a time when longer maturity interest rates spiked. Performance also benefitted from credit spreads decreasing in the face of the vaccine news.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;The welcome vaccine news and clarity on the presidential election winner both sparked a meaningful global equity rally in November. Bonds typically sell-off when sentiment is high as investors chase the stock action and sell their safe-haven fixed income investments. That pushes their yield up. Sure enough, the yield on the touchstone US 10-year maturity treasury bonds started the month at 0.87% and traded as high as 0.97%. However, the yield came back down to end the month only 3 basis points lower at 0.84% amidst burgeoning infections and the inability of the Senate to act on much-needed stimulus. US economic data has consequently been a little weaker than expected and the US Federal Reserve (Fed) has now made the implicit explicit admitting that it may well need to augment it’s $80bn/month bond buybacks to provide further stimulus.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;As telegraphed, the Royal Bank of Australia (RBA) cut their overnight rate from 0.25% to 0.10% on November 3rd while being clear they thought negative interest rates were “not sensible”. They also increased the maturity and size of their bond buy-backs to A$100bn over the next 6 months. In addition, they extended their purchases to state bonds (some of which we have been buying and which performed very well on the back of the announcement). Despite all this, Aussie bond yields did rise on the back of a stronger than expected economy coming out of the Victoria lockdown. 10-year bond yields consequently rose from 0.83% to 0.90% over the month.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;New Zealand’s longer-term interest rates spiked in November with the NZ 10-year government bond closing the month up 32 basis points to 0.85%. The predominant reason for the spike was a marked change of tone from the Reserve Bank at its Monetary Policy meeting. After months of “we are not bluffing” rhetoric on their pursuit of negative interest rates, they unexpectedly acknowledged that the NZ economy was doing better than expected. The icing on the cake was an exchange of letters between Finance Minister Grant Robertson and RBNZ Governor Adrian Orr. Robertson asked the Reserve Bank to consider taking house prices into account in its setting of monetary policy while Orr demurred batting the responsibility back to the government. The market responded by pricing out any future negative interest rates causing longer maturity bonds to sell-off.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;h3&gt;Positioning&lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Having taken some chips off the table in October, November was quite quiet. We were net sellers of long-dated maturities, selling more 2028 and 2031 &lt;strong&gt;NZ Government&lt;/strong&gt; (rated AA+) bonds while buying the new 10-year &lt;strong&gt;World Bank&lt;/strong&gt; (AAA) issue.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Right now, we are focusing on shorter maturities (albeit there may be some yearend anomalies that might be worth pursuing in longer maturity bonds). We like shorter bonds because, even if not going negative, it’s still quite likely that the Official Cash Rate (OCR) will remain very low for the foreseeable future. There may even be an Aussie-like cut to 0.1% given the unwelcome rise of the NZD vs. US$ above 70¢.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;We purchased new &lt;strong&gt;Chorus&lt;/strong&gt; (BBB) 7-year bonds, having gained comfort that the buildout of the unique national fibre network is behind them, after the NZ bond sell-off. We also added short maturity bonds of &lt;strong&gt;Meridian&lt;/strong&gt; (BBB+) and &lt;strong&gt;Z-Energy&lt;/strong&gt; (NR).&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;img src="https://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=703880&amp;amp;k=14&amp;amp;r=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.kiwiinvest.co.nz%2Finvestment-insights%2Fmarket-update-november&amp;amp;bu=https%253A%252F%252Fwww.kiwiinvest.co.nz%252Finvestment-insights&amp;amp;bvt=rss" alt="" width="1" height="1" style="min-height:1px!important;width:1px!important;border-width:0!important;margin-top:0!important;margin-bottom:0!important;margin-right:0!important;margin-left:0!important;padding-top:0!important;padding-bottom:0!important;padding-right:0!important;padding-left:0!important; "&gt;</content:encoded>
      <category>(Our Updates) Market Updates</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Dec 2020 03:34:49 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/market-update-november</guid>
      <dc:date>2020-12-07T03:34:49Z</dc:date>
      <dc:creator>Robert Murray</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pandemic Baby Boom a Bust</title>
      <link>https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/pandemic-baby-boom-a-bust</link>
      <description>&lt;div class="hs-featured-image-wrapper"&gt; 
 &lt;a href="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/pandemic-baby-boom-a-bust" title="" class="hs-featured-image-link"&gt; &lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hubfs/Fertility%26COVID-600px.jpg" alt="couple in bed wearing face masks" class="hs-featured-image" style="width:auto !important; max-width:50%; float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;"&gt; &lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hs-fs/hubfs/Fertility%26COVID-600px.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;name=Fertility%26COVID-600px.jpg" alt="couple in bed wearing face masks" width="300" style="width: 300px; float: right; margin: 0px 0px 10px 19px;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;During the early stages of the pandemic, a number of pundits confidently predicted that lockdowns would lead to a baby boom, the rationale being that bored young couples would run out of Netflix shows to watch and spend more time in the bedroom.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;This was always a dubious piece of logic. People don’t generally make important life decisions based on temporary gaps in their social calendar. Even if couples spent all their lockdown time in bed, it doesn’t follow that they’d suddenly forget how contraception works.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In fact, economists and fertility experts around the world believe the opposite is happening. Couples are having fewer children, and we are in the middle of a baby bust.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;History shows that fewer children are born during times of economic uncertainty, and when you add the safety concerns of a pandemic into the mix, it’s not surprising that many wealthy nations expect 2021 to bring a slump in new births.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;In the US, the Brookings Institution estimates there will be 3.3 million babies born in 2021, a 13% drop from 3.8m in 2019. In China, analysts at Barclays recently lowered their expectations of 2021 births from 15.7m to 13.0m, a fall of 11% from 2019 levels.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;It’s a similar story around the world, particularly in developed nations where fertility rates were already trending lower. NZ’s fertility rate recently hit its lowest level on record – and that’s before any Covid-19 impact.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Spare a thought for the Millennials aged 29-36, who have now had two major economic shocks to contend with. The Great Recession of 2008 pushed back career and economic milestones for many young people, forcing them to delay starting a family. For these couples, COVID-19 has come at exactly the wrong time.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Hoping for a baby boom once the pandemic is over may also be wishful thinking. Demographic studies show that women who delay having babies at any point either don’t have them or have fewer than originally planned. So, while there may be a short-term spike in pregnancies when the pandemic is behind us, we could soon return to a longer-term period of decline.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;This concerns governments because of the impact on future aggregate demand and the shrinking pool of workers that will have to support an aging population. That’s why countries like Finland and Singapore are offering financial incentives to have more children. China is expected to include similar incentives in its next five-year plan.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;But a lower fertility rate has implications for investors, too.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;There are the obvious losers in the baby products industry – nappies, infant formula, toys. Given the size of the Chinese infant formula market, this will be an earnings headwind for several large multinationals in 2021.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The impact on housing should also be considered. While the pre-pandemic demographics looked favourable for US housing, with the chunky Millennial cohort moving through their thirties, a sharp drop in fertility rates may throw a spanner in the works. Delays in starting a family will inevitably have a negative impact on housing demand.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;On the flipside, there could be an increase in discretionary expenditures that childfree couples veer towards – e.g. travel, restaurants, and clothing. Spending on pets, or fur babies, may also see a boost.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;These are just a few examples of the sensitivities thrown up by changes in demographic assumptions. It’s not a precise science, and some of the changes are likely to be at the margin. But in our view, rather than leading to a baby boom, Covid-19 threatens to accelerate the long-term trend towards smaller families. In the absence of significant government assistance, perhaps the only way to reverse the trend will be a sustained period of global economic prosperity.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;As thematic investors, we look to identify and leverage the global ‘themes’ and trends that underpin and shape market performance.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nathan Field is the Portfolio Manager of Kiwi Invest’s &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/globalthematic"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Global Thematic Fund.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;img src="https://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=703880&amp;amp;k=14&amp;amp;r=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.kiwiinvest.co.nz%2Finvestment-insights%2Fpandemic-baby-boom-a-bust&amp;amp;bu=https%253A%252F%252Fwww.kiwiinvest.co.nz%252Finvestment-insights&amp;amp;bvt=rss" alt="" width="1" height="1" style="min-height:1px!important;width:1px!important;border-width:0!important;margin-top:0!important;margin-bottom:0!important;margin-right:0!important;margin-left:0!important;padding-top:0!important;padding-bottom:0!important;padding-right:0!important;padding-left:0!important; "&gt;</content:encoded>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:57:08 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>nathan.field@kiwiwealth.co.nz (Nathan Field)</author>
      <guid>https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/pandemic-baby-boom-a-bust</guid>
      <dc:date>2020-12-03T00:57:08Z</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Market finds comfort in gridlock</title>
      <link>https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/us-election-comfort-in-gridlock</link>
      <description>&lt;div class="hs-featured-image-wrapper"&gt; 
 &lt;a href="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/us-election-comfort-in-gridlock" title="" class="hs-featured-image-link"&gt; &lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hubfs/WhiteHouseVCapitol.jpg" alt="The Market finds comfort in gridlock" class="hs-featured-image" style="width:auto !important; max-width:50%; float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;"&gt; &lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;    
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;While the US election didn’t produce the ‘Blue Wave’ that many Democrats had hoped for, it seems on track to deliver excellent results in market terms.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hs-fs/hubfs/WhiteHouseVCapitol.jpg?width=300&amp;amp;name=WhiteHouseVCapitol.jpg" alt="white house vs. capitol building" width="300" style="width: 300px; float: right; margin: 0px 0px 10px 19px;"&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;While the US election didn’t produce the ‘Blue Wave’ that many Democrats had hoped for, it seems on track to deliver excellent results in market terms.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;While several uncertainties remain - such as Trump legal challenges and two vital Senate run-off elections next January - enough pieces are falling in to place to give markets reasonable confidence in the direction we’re headed.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Of course, even as we work through the impact of the election, the market sent clear signals that a Covid-19 vaccine ‘trumps’ all other events. The news on a promising vaccine from Pfizer greatly outweighed the election saga - but as that future unfolds, we must also weigh up how a new political regime will handle the pandemic and the recovery.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Baring a dramatic and unlikely judicial win by the Trump campaign, Joe Biden will be the President of the United States from 20 January 2021. While this outcome was largely expected, the closeness of the race surprised many and has allowed Trump to publicly challenge&amp;nbsp;the end result. The Senate, while still not decided, is likely to remain in Republican hands - unless runoff elections for Georgia’s two Senate seats ‘turn it blue’ on 5 January. However, with Democrats needing both wins for Senate control, and Republican candidates currently&amp;nbsp;favoured&amp;nbsp;in both races, the most likely outcome is that Biden will rule over a divided Congress.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;While a divided government may appear unhealthy for many Americans, the market saw it as a helpful handbrake on issues such as government spending, increased regulation, and tax increases. Fiscal stimulus is likely to be smaller if Republican sign off is necessary - and may be postponed if the economy continues to gradually improve, with Pfizer’s vaccine news adding further complexity.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Equity markets were more hopeful that a divided government would lower the likelihood of tax increases and increased regulation. President-elect Biden’s proposals to raise corporate tax rates to 28% from&amp;nbsp;21&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;%, and&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;increase personal income tax for those earning over $400,000 are unlikely to progress through a Republican Senate.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Likewise, ambitious spending projects such as his $1.7 trillion clean energy plan, and expanding the Affordable Care Act, may be reined in by a Republican Senate. From a market point of view, this may deliver a reasonable amount of fiscal stimulus if clearly needed, but with less the risk of higher taxes.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Despite this - and the overwhelming impact of a future Covid vaccine - the election outcome still has long-term consequences. Health care, sustainable energy, and infrastructure will most likely still benefit from a Biden presidency, even if Congress is split, but the magnitude of the potential investment is now limited. On the other hand, it may become easier for Biden to find common ground and focus on foreign policy and renegotiating trade deals.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;In these volatile times, we remain focused on building a diversified portfolio of high-quality, liquid investments that seeks to weather the storm and take advantage of market opportunities.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;img src="https://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=703880&amp;amp;k=14&amp;amp;r=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.kiwiinvest.co.nz%2Finvestment-insights%2Fus-election-comfort-in-gridlock&amp;amp;bu=https%253A%252F%252Fwww.kiwiinvest.co.nz%252Finvestment-insights&amp;amp;bvt=rss" alt="" width="1" height="1" style="min-height:1px!important;width:1px!important;border-width:0!important;margin-top:0!important;margin-bottom:0!important;margin-right:0!important;margin-left:0!important;padding-top:0!important;padding-bottom:0!important;padding-right:0!important;padding-left:0!important; "&gt;</content:encoded>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 03:33:03 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>frank.braden@kiwiwealth.co.nz (Frank Braden)</author>
      <guid>https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/us-election-comfort-in-gridlock</guid>
      <dc:date>2020-11-12T03:33:03Z</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investment Update October 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/market-update-october</link>
      <description>&lt;div class="hs-featured-image-wrapper"&gt; 
 &lt;a href="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/market-update-october" title="" class="hs-featured-image-link"&gt; &lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hubfs/GlobalMarketUpdate-OctNov-1200px.png" alt="Investment Update October 2020" class="hs-featured-image" style="width:auto !important; max-width:50%; float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;"&gt; &lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;    
&lt;h2&gt;Global Market View&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Two themes were top of mind for investors in the month of October, the second major wave of Covid-19 outbreak across Europe, and the highly anticipated upcoming US elections in early November. Volatility climbed to levels seen back in June, and developed markets broadly declined. The MSCI All Country index (NZD hedged) fell 2.5% over the month, although several bright spots were seen across emerging markets. Declines were concentrated around the energy, healthcare and tech sectors, while utilities and communication services outperformed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;Global Market View&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Two themes were top of mind for investors in the month of October, the second major wave of Covid-19 outbreak across Europe, and the highly anticipated upcoming US elections in early November. Volatility climbed to levels seen back in June, and developed markets broadly declined. The MSCI All Country index (NZD hedged) fell 2.5% over the month, although several bright spots were seen across emerging markets. Declines were concentrated around the energy, healthcare and tech sectors, while utilities and communication services outperformed.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Over the course of the month, markets observed the Covid-19 situation deteriorate across much of Europe. Daily new cases &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;and hospitalisations surged drastically as localised restrictions failed to curb the rate of spread. Total cases in the region &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;have now reached a milestone of 10 million cases, and many authorities have now or are in the process of implementing &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;nation-wide lockdowns. This raises doubts around just how effective a curve suppression approach is. Economic impacts &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;aside, the increasing psychological pressures has made social disorder become somewhat of a rising concern with protests &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;breaking out across the likes Spain, Italy and France.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Across the Atlantic, the United States weren’t immune. To the surprise of many, President Trump along with key members of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;the White House tested positive for the coronavirus at the start of the month and by the end, daily new cases in the country &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;had risen to record highs of almost 100 thousand. The gridlock in the fiscal stimulus package negotiations remains a sore &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;point, the tug-o-war between lawmakers to date yielded no substantial results and was one of the main culprits for the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;increased volatility over the month.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;That said, much of the focus was instead directed to the upcoming election on 3rd of November. National polls favoured &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Democratic nominee Joe Biden over the month and the markets responded well, pricing in a potential Democratic sweep &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;into the Presidency, Senate and the House. Generally, it is not out of the ordinary for market volatility to remain elevated in &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;the period leading up to an election, but this typically dissipates afterwards. It is largely expected that a Biden victory would &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;bring forth greater fiscal stimulus, which a positive for the economy. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Our portfolios remain well diversified, liquid and ready to be tailored whatever the outcome may turn out to be. As you’re &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;reading this, the votes will hopefully have been counted. We look forward to sharing with you our post-election thoughts &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;shortly.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hs-fs/hubfs/GlobalMarketUpdate-OctNov-1200px.png?width=796&amp;amp;name=GlobalMarketUpdate-OctNov-1200px.png" alt="GlobalMarketUpdate-OctNov-1200px" width="796" style="background-color: transparent; width: 796px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="#growth-performance"&gt;Growth Performance&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; |&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="#growth-positioning"&gt;Growth Positioning&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; |&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="#fixed-interest-performance"&gt;Fixed Interest Performance&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; |&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="#fixed-interest-positioning"&gt;Fixed Interest Positioning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;h2&gt;Growth&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hs-fs/hubfs/nathan-field.png?width=90&amp;amp;name=nathan-field.png" alt="nathan-field" width="90" style="background-color: transparent; width: 90px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hs-fs/hubfs/Steffan-3.png?width=90&amp;amp;name=Steffan-3.png" alt="Steffan-3" width="90" style="background-color: transparent; width: 90px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;by Nathan Field, Portfolio Manager - Global Thematic and Steffan Berridge, Head of Quantitative Strategy&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;h3&gt;Performance&lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Kiwi Wealth Growth Fund (Growth PIE) returned -1.92% after tax and fees in October, 0.71% ahead of the MSCI All Country &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;benchmark which returned -2.64%. All three of the underlying equity strategies contributed positively to relative performance this &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;month, and in addition the alternative assets outperformed cash and equities. The Kiwi dollar weakened slightly against the US &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;greenback last month which is a positive for foreign currency returns.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Global Thematic finished 0.72% ahead of the benchmark in a volatile month for equity markets. US banks were among the best &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;performers of the month amid a slight rise in interest rates and hopes of a Democrat sweep in the US elections (which didn’t &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;transpire). Similar political hopes were behind the outperformance of construction materials stocks Vulcan Materials and Martin &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Marietta. High growth technology stocks lagged the market in October as investors questioned high valuations and weighed &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;regulatory risks.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Global Quantitative fund were 0.77% ahead of the MSCI AC benchmark as a new coronavirus wave hit the US and Europe &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;and the world steadied for the American Peoples’ assessment of President Trump in early November. The virus resurgence &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;pushed markets down for the month, with COVID-defensive sectors like Utilities and Communications outperforming while &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Energy, Tech and Healthcare lagged. Crude oil was down 10% while treasury yields were up 17bps. Outperformance was driven by &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Healthcare and Industrials positions with &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;United Therapeutics and Quanta Services&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; delivering stronger than expected earnings, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;while the best performer overall was &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dunkin’ Brands &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;which also surprised on the upside in its release. Our worst sector was &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Communications where underweights in &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alphabet&lt;/strong&gt;,&lt;strong&gt; Snap&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tencent&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; were a headwind.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;h3&gt;Positioning&lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;In Global Thematic, we had positioned the portfolio to be resilient under any political outcome in the US, having &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;a mix of secular growth and cyclical themes. The combination of a (likely) Democrat president and Republican &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Senate certainly weakens the case for some cyclical and interest rate sensitive stocks, but we will reassess our &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;suite of themes once the final votes are counted.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;For Global Quantitative, Our top-down positioning targets higher quality sectors more suited to the current &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;environment like Technology and Industrials. Stock selection favours companies with attractive metrics across &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;earnings quality, capital efficiency, valuations, sentiment and sustainability. Over the month, we increased our &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;allocation to Materials &lt;strong&gt;(&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Linde&lt;/strong&gt;,&lt;strong&gt; Nitto Denko&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;) and Healthcare (&lt;strong&gt;I&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DEXX Labs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;), and reduced allocation to Industrials &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eiffage, J.B. Hunt Transport&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;) and Utilities (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evergy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;). Industrials, Technology and Discretionary remain our &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;favoured sectors while Financials and Energy remain our largest underweights.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;h2&gt;Fixed Interest&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hs-fs/hubfs/images/team/blog-authors/diana-g-125px.png?width=90&amp;amp;name=diana-g-125px.png" alt="diana-g-125px" width="90" style="width: 90px; float: left; margin: 0px 10px 10px 0px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;by Diana Gordon, Head of Fixed Interest&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;h3&gt;Performance&lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Kiwi Wealth Fixed Interest Fund (Fixed Interest PIE) returned 0.12% after fees and taxes in October outperforming its &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;benchmark which returned -0.20%. The outperformance can largely be attributed to having a lower maturity than the benchmark &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;at time when longer maturity interest rates increased. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We haven’t talked much about the US in a while because, well, there wasn’t much to say. Their 10-year maturity treasury bonds &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;have traded in a tight range for months. Not so in October which saw that yield increase from 0.68% to 0.87%. What drove this &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;move? Most of it seems related to large short positions as speculators position themselves for a Biden sweep. The thesis is that &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;there will be huge infrastructure stimulus kicking in after a January legislation. Also, economic activity has picked up with Q3 GDP &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;rising a higher than expected 33.1% from the lows of Q2. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;However, two forces will likely keep US treasury yields, the touchstone for our own bond market, from rising too far. Firstly, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;surging infections will likely depress economic activity albeit not likely with the degree of lockdowns seen previously. Secondly, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;the US Federal Reserve is a long-term manipulator of rates. Only so far and no farther is likely their mantra before they come &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;stepping back in to buy bonds. What the definition of so far is unknown but it’s highly unlikely to be much over 1.25%, if that.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Talking of buying bonds, the Reserve Bank of Australia (RBA) came off the fence in October hinting about increasing their own &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;bond buy-backs. A further overnight interest rate cut to 0.1% was also hinted at likely to happen after their 3rd November meeting &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;(which they did, more of that next month). Their 10-year bond rate consequently only rose marginally from 0.79% to 0.83% over &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;the month.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;New Zealand’s longer-term interest rates followed the US up with the NZ 10-year government bond closing the month up 3.5 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;basis points to 0.53%. They outperformed the US due to some tempering by Australia’s move and the relentless reminders from &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;our Reserve Bank that they will be cutting the Official Cash Rate (OCR) after March next year. While our economy continues to &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;perform well, the RBNZ remain concerned about the global economy.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;h3&gt;Positioning&lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We took some chips off the table in October, selling some of our longer 2031, 2037 and 2041 maturity &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Zealand Government&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; bonds and switching into lower maturity &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New South Wales bonds (AAA) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;and the newly &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;syndicated &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;New Zealand Government (AA+) &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;2028 maturity. The rationale was twofold. Firstly, there is the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;higher risk that longer maturity interest rates would rise in the event of a Biden win, dragging Australia and New &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Zealand rates along and thus leading to lower bond prices. We also expected the Reserve Bank of Australia &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;to target their state bonds for repurchase in early November. We added a few corporate names, Australian &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;supermarket chain &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coles (BBB+),US telecom giants Verizon (BBB+)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AT&amp;amp;T (BBB)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt; all in Australian dollars. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;We also purchased NZ utility, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vector (BBB+) &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;span&gt;at new issue.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;img src="https://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=703880&amp;amp;k=14&amp;amp;r=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.kiwiinvest.co.nz%2Finvestment-insights%2Fmarket-update-october&amp;amp;bu=https%253A%252F%252Fwww.kiwiinvest.co.nz%252Finvestment-insights&amp;amp;bvt=rss" alt="" width="1" height="1" style="min-height:1px!important;width:1px!important;border-width:0!important;margin-top:0!important;margin-bottom:0!important;margin-right:0!important;margin-left:0!important;padding-top:0!important;padding-bottom:0!important;padding-right:0!important;padding-left:0!important; "&gt;</content:encoded>
      <category>(Our Updates) Market Updates</category>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Nov 2020 01:28:44 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>di.zhu@kiwiinvest.co.nz (Di Zhu)</author>
      <guid>https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/market-update-october</guid>
      <dc:date>2020-11-06T01:28:44Z</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A look at 'the road ahead' - from our Kiwi Investment team</title>
      <link>https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/a-look-at-the-road-ahead-from-our-kiwi-investment-team</link>
      <description>&lt;div class="hs-featured-image-wrapper"&gt; 
 &lt;a href="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/a-look-at-the-road-ahead-from-our-kiwi-investment-team" title="" class="hs-featured-image-link"&gt; &lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hubfs/RoadAheadImage.jpg" alt="the road ahead" class="hs-featured-image" style="width:auto !important; max-width:50%; float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;"&gt; &lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;    
&lt;p&gt;Test&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Test&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;img src="https://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=703880&amp;amp;k=14&amp;amp;r=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.kiwiinvest.co.nz%2Finvestment-insights%2Fa-look-at-the-road-ahead-from-our-kiwi-investment-team&amp;amp;bu=https%253A%252F%252Fwww.kiwiinvest.co.nz%252Finvestment-insights&amp;amp;bvt=rss" alt="" width="1" height="1" style="min-height:1px!important;width:1px!important;border-width:0!important;margin-top:0!important;margin-bottom:0!important;margin-right:0!important;margin-left:0!important;padding-top:0!important;padding-bottom:0!important;padding-right:0!important;padding-left:0!important; "&gt;</content:encoded>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2020 06:11:39 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/a-look-at-the-road-ahead-from-our-kiwi-investment-team</guid>
      <dc:date>2020-10-28T06:11:39Z</dc:date>
      <dc:creator>Kiwi Invest</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investment Update September 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/market-update-september</link>
      <description>&lt;div class="hs-featured-image-wrapper"&gt; 
 &lt;a href="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/market-update-september" title="" class="hs-featured-image-link"&gt; &lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hubfs/GlobalMarketUpdate-SeptOct-1200px.png" alt="Investment Update September 2020" class="hs-featured-image" style="width:auto !important; max-width:50%; float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;"&gt; &lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;    
&lt;h2&gt;Global Market View&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;After a steady climb higher over recent months, equity markets took a breather in September as investors gauged the prospect of a second wave of COVID-19 infections in the Northern hemisphere alongside mixed views on the timeline of a potential vaccine. The MSCI All Investment Update October 2020 Country index (NZD hedged) fell 2.8% over the month, with all the major markets showing weakness except for Japan.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;Global Market View&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;After a steady climb higher over recent months, equity markets took a breather in September as investors gauged the prospect of a second wave of COVID-19 infections in the Northern hemisphere alongside mixed views on the timeline of a potential vaccine. The MSCI All Investment Update October 2020 Country index (NZD hedged) fell 2.8% over the month, with all the major markets showing weakness except for Japan.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Even technology giants like Apple (-10.3% in September), Amazon (-8.8%) and Microsoft (-6.7%) finally succumbed to profit-taking after their incredible runs in the year to date.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;While equity markets were weak, there was nothing particularly new or unexpected in September’s news flow. But with share prices starting the month 66% above their March lows, a pullback was always on the cards, especially as we head towards the US presidential elections in early November.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;The Democrat nominee, Joe Biden, is currently the favourite to win the White House, which would have puts and takes for equity markets. Higher corporate taxes and increased regulations would likely weigh on certain sectors, but heavier spending on green energy and infrastructure could offset. In our view, the greatest risk of the election is a prolonged period of uncertainty over a disputed result, which could shake confidence in an already tenuous economic recovery.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;The pandemic is the other significant risk weighing on investor sentiment, with infection rates on the rise again in Europe, and US cases stubbornly high. Even though patient outcomes have greatly improved, it is becoming increasingly clear that until an effective vaccine becomes widely available, economic activity will struggle to return to normal.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Nevertheless, low interest rates should continue to support share prices. The US 10-year yield barely moved in September, finishing the month at a miserly 0.68%. We see little evidence of inflation or economic strength that would cause central banks to tighten monetary conditions, and while COVID-19 continues to cast a shadow over consumer confidence, the low interest rate environment is likely to persist.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;However, if the Democrats win the White House and an effective vaccine is found, the situation could change rapidly, especially if markets reset inflation expectations. Regardless, our large, liquid investments mean we can swiftly reconfigure the portfolio to suit any climate. As this challenging year has already proven, maintaining a focus on the long term is crucial, as opportunities can manifest in even the most trying economic conditions.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hs-fs/hubfs/GlobalMarketUpdate-SeptOct-1200px.png?width=796&amp;amp;name=GlobalMarketUpdate-SeptOct-1200px.png" alt="GlobalMarketUpdate-SeptOct-1200px" width="796" style="background-color: transparent; width: 796px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="#growth-performance"&gt;Growth Performance&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; |&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="#growth-positioning"&gt;Growth Positioning&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; |&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="#fixed-interest-performance"&gt;Fixed Interest Performance&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; |&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="#fixed-interest-positioning"&gt;Fixed Interest Positioning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;h2&gt;Growth&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hs-fs/hubfs/nathan-field.png?width=90&amp;amp;name=nathan-field.png" alt="nathan-field" width="90" style="background-color: transparent; width: 90px;"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hs-fs/hubfs/images/team/paul-shucksmith-round-bg.png?width=90&amp;amp;name=paul-shucksmith-round-bg.png" alt="paul-shucksmith-round-bg" width="90" style="background-color: transparent; width: 90px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;by Nathan Field, Portfolio Manager - Global Thematic and Paul Shucksmith, Quantitative Developer&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;h3&gt;Performance&lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;The Kiwi Wealth Growth Fund (Growth PIE) returned -1.45% after tax and fees in September, 0.64% ahead of the MSCI All Country benchmark. Both Global Thematic and Global Quantitative strategies contributed positively to relative performance this month, while Core Global and the alternative assets were drags. The Kiwi dollar weakened against the US greenback last month which was a tailwind for foreign currency returns.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Global Thematic managed a positive 0.24% return despite the weakness in equity markets, outperforming the benchmark by 1.24%. Our US homebuilding and public construction themes performed strongly, with quarry companies &lt;strong&gt;Martin Marietta&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Vulcan Materials&lt;/strong&gt; both rising over 14%. Athleisure stocks also had a strong month after &lt;strong&gt;Nike&lt;/strong&gt;’s blowout quarterly earnings result, although &lt;strong&gt;Lululemon&lt;/strong&gt; fell victim to profit taking. Large cap tech names like &lt;strong&gt;Apple, Microsoft&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Facebook&lt;/strong&gt; were notable laggards in September after a lengthy period of outperformance.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;The Global Quantitative fund returned -0.67% in September, 0.33% ahead of the MSCI AC benchmark as most sectors ended the month lower although a fall in the NZD improved the picture somewhat. September saw a change in fortune for the large-cap growth names that have been leading the markets’ recovery from the Coronavirus Crash with concerns around inflated valuations and investor crowding coming to bear. Energy sold-off heavily, with the WTI falling below $40 a barrel at one point as global demand softened and Gulf Coast activity resumed after Hurricanes Laura and Marco. Industrials and Utilities the leading sectors.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;Outperformance was driven by our focus on Asian tech names (&lt;strong&gt;United Microelectronics, Samsung&lt;/strong&gt;) and our underweight in Banks (avoiding names like &lt;strong&gt;Citigroup&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Bank of America&lt;/strong&gt;) and Energy (&lt;strong&gt;Exxon, Chevron, BP&lt;/strong&gt; all experienced large declines). Health Care was the biggest drag on performance with &lt;strong&gt;Illumina&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Henry Schein&lt;/strong&gt; the worst positions.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;h3&gt;Positioning&lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;In Global Thematic, we have continued to tilt the portfolio towards re-opening themes, building positions in offprice retail stocks like &lt;strong&gt;Ross Stores&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;TJX&lt;/strong&gt;, as well as selected restaurant stocks. We also increased our weight in some of the large cap technology names that were hit hard in September (&lt;strong&gt;Amazon, Apple&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;For Global Quantitative, our top-down positioning targets higher quality sectors more suited to the current environment like Technology and Industrials. Stock selection favours companies with attractive metrics across earnings quality, capital efficiency, valuations, sentiment and sustainability. Over the month, we increased our allocation to Financials (&lt;strong&gt;E.SUN Financial, China Life Insurance&lt;/strong&gt;) and Industrials (&lt;strong&gt;Deutsche Post&lt;/strong&gt;), trimming Health Care (&lt;strong&gt;Abbvie, Illumina&lt;/strong&gt;) and Staples (&lt;strong&gt;a2 Milk&lt;/strong&gt;). Industrials, Technology and Discretionary remain our favoured sectors. Health Care has been brought down to neutral while Financials and Energy remain our largest underweights.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;h2&gt;Fixed Interest&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hs-fs/hubfs/images/team/blog-authors/diana-g-125px.png?width=90&amp;amp;name=diana-g-125px.png" alt="diana-g-125px" width="90" style="width: 90px; float: left; margin: 0px 10px 10px 0px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;by DIana Gordon, Head of Fixed Interest&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;h3&gt;Performance&lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;The Kiwi Wealth Fixed Interest Fund (Fixed Interest PIE) returned 0.39% after fees and taxes in September underperforming its benchmark which returned 0.58%. The underperformance can mostly be attributed to trying to keep up with a relentless Reserve Bank-led crunch on interest rates. Also, corporate bonds spreads (extra yield a company pays versus a government bond) widened relative to NZ Government Bonds over the month.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;September was largely a sleepy month for foreign government bonds, trading in their habitual range of interest rates. The interest rate on a US Government Treasury bond declined from 0.70% to 0.68% over the month. On the margin, there were cracks as the Bank of England began – like New Zealand – to make noises over preparing to cut interest rates to negative levels. This was amidst Coronavirus rates beginning to rise again and a consequentially dourer economic outlook. This, and the constant noise from the hotly contested US presidential election, also pushed credit spreads wider. After an unequivocally dovish (lower interest rates for longer) statement in August, the RBNZ continued to leave no doubt that negative interest rates are on the cards. As at the end of the month, the Official Cash Rate (OCR) currently at 0.25% is expected to be ~ -0.2% by October next year. It’s clear that the gloves will be off to cut the OCR after March 2021 (the RBNZ having affirmed that it will keep the OCR at 0.25% until then). The one change in the Reserve Bank’s position at its 6-weekly meeting was that it stated that it would like its new Funding for Lending Program to be in operation by Christmas. This facility would allow the RBNZ to lend to banks at the Official Cash Rate (OCR) rate (or thereabouts), which would provide cheap funds and allow banks to make cheaper loans (mortgages etc) to their customers. Conversely, it will also likely suppress term deposit rates even more (though we don’t believe below zero). Two other factors pushed New Zealand interest rates lower (and hence bond prices up) apart from the strong jawboning from the RBNZ backed up by solid government bond buying. On Sep 16th the Treasury published its Preelection Economic and Fiscal Update (PREFU) forecast stating that the NZ budget deficit should be NZ$15bn less than expected over the next two years thus reducing the prospective supply of bonds. Also, the next big government issuance was a bit shorter than the markets thought so all ended up in a bit of a grab for positive yields even as rates sank, some shorter maturity bonds trading below 0%. Consequently, the interest rate on a 10-year NZ government bond bucked the global trend declining from 0.63% to 0.51% over the month ironically despite our Coronavirus outbreak being increasingly under control. All the signs from the RBNZ is that they fear deflationary effects from global weakness as government support begin to decline. The path of least regret for them is lower for longer interest rates.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;h3&gt;Positioning&lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: left;"&gt;We continued to focus on high quality credits over September, as we remain very selective about the types of names and companies we want to own. We added &lt;strong&gt;Housing New Zealand&lt;/strong&gt; (AA+), &lt;strong&gt;Asian Development Bank&lt;/strong&gt; (AAA), &lt;strong&gt;International Bank of Reconstruction and Development&lt;/strong&gt; (AAA) and Norwegian State Housing Authority,&lt;strong&gt; KBN&lt;/strong&gt; (AAA). The New Zealand company bond market began to heat up in September and we purchased &lt;strong&gt;Port of Tauranga&lt;/strong&gt; (A-) and &lt;strong&gt;Mercury&lt;/strong&gt; (BBB+) new issues. Overseas we began to add a few names like &lt;strong&gt;AT&amp;amp;T&lt;/strong&gt; (BBB) and &lt;strong&gt;Nestle&lt;/strong&gt; (AA-) and we hope to add more if high quality company credit spreads continue to widen. Given the RBNZ’s tack, we’ve been big proponents of the New Zealand bond market for a while which has paid off. However, we did dip our toes in the Australian State market, establishing a position in New South Wales bonds which we saw as very cheap relative to New Zealand Government Bonds.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;img src="https://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=703880&amp;amp;k=14&amp;amp;r=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.kiwiinvest.co.nz%2Finvestment-insights%2Fmarket-update-september&amp;amp;bu=https%253A%252F%252Fwww.kiwiinvest.co.nz%252Finvestment-insights&amp;amp;bvt=rss" alt="" width="1" height="1" style="min-height:1px!important;width:1px!important;border-width:0!important;margin-top:0!important;margin-bottom:0!important;margin-right:0!important;margin-left:0!important;padding-top:0!important;padding-bottom:0!important;padding-right:0!important;padding-left:0!important; "&gt;</content:encoded>
      <category>(Our Updates) Market Updates</category>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 02:15:14 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>nathan.field@kiwiwealth.co.nz (Nathan Field)</author>
      <guid>https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/market-update-september</guid>
      <dc:date>2020-10-07T02:15:14Z</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kiwi Invest secures Movac investment for Kiwi Wealth KiwiSaver Scheme</title>
      <link>https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/kiwi-invest-secures-movac-investment</link>
      <description>&lt;div class="hs-featured-image-wrapper"&gt; 
 &lt;a href="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/kiwi-invest-secures-movac-investment" title="" class="hs-featured-image-link"&gt; &lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hubfs/Movac-Primary-RGB-72-Transparent_150402-2.png" alt="movac logo" class="hs-featured-image" style="width:auto !important; max-width:50%; float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;"&gt; &lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;    
&lt;p&gt;Venture capital firm Movac has secured investment from Kiwi Invest for the Kiwi Wealth KiwiSaver Scheme to become a cornerstone investor in the new Movac Fund 5 technology fund. It marks the first time an institutional player within the KiwiSaver space has entered the growth and venture capital ecosystem at this scale. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Movac Fund 5 is a $200-$250m growth capital fund which has a specific New Zealand focus and will invest over time in technology start-ups and growth companies. Its design allows it to support early stage companies as they grow, with capital available for later funding rounds, as well as investing in later-stage companies. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Kiwi Invest is the investment manager for the Kiwi Wealth KiwiSaver Scheme and has committed up to $54m in capital over the lifetime of the Fund. It joins contributions from NZ Super Fund ($70m), NZ Growth Capital Partners (up to $30m), with the balance from experienced entrepreneurs, family offices, individual investors, and several iwi. First close of Fund 5 will be September 23, and second close on 23 October.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Founded in 1998, Movac is a well-established and resourced venture capital firm in the technology sector and was selected by Kiwi Invest after a thorough due diligence process. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Simon O’Grady, Chief Investment Officer, Kiwi Invest, says, “Kiwi Invest views this as an important first step towards a potential series of private equity investments and the beginning of a pipeline of work over the coming years to build out this asset class. Kiwi Invest may look to build and diversify in this sector, based on the manager, geography and asset type from an investment perspective.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“Movac has a talented and experienced investment team, sound and well-tested processes, and a strong track record in supporting successful New Zealand tech start-ups and growth companies, helping them to grow their businesses globally.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“The market is changing and those providing capital are having to venture more into the private, unlisted sector on behalf of those seeking returns on investment. Kiwi Invest saw that it was the right time, with the right manager, and in the right sector for this investment.” &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The investment will be staggered over time as Movac goes through the process of selecting companies for funding and working directly to move them through the growth stages. Fund 5 is focused on backing this process in a graduated way, supported by thorough due diligence by all parties.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The longer-term nature of the investment is consistent with the Kiwi Wealth KiwiSaver Scheme’s function as a long-term savings vehicle. It offers an opportunity for returns while remaining a small proportion of the diversified growth assets in the Scheme.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Phil McCaw, Managing Partner at Movac, says, “We are pleased to have successfully raised Movac Fund 5, and delighted to have Kiwi Invest on-board as a cornerstone investor – this is also the introduction of Kiwi Invest to venture capital investment.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“I’m delighted to have the support of Kiwi Invest as a cornerstone investor in Movac Fund 5. For many years I’ve been a vocal proponent of KiwiSaver managers allocating a small portion of their funds to the New Zealand venture capital sector. Not only has there been the potential for exceptional returns as we’ve experienced to date, but it’s also where fantastic innovation and job creation occurs. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“It is great to have a major KiwiSaver investment manager in the growth and venture capital ecosystem supporting the rapid expansion of local businesses. This long-term alignment is innovative and shows leadership and a new maturity in New Zealand tech and the investment sector. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“I congratulate the Kiwi Invest team for showing true market leadership in the sector with their significant investment in a venture capital fund like Movac Fund 5, and we look forward to working hard on their behalf to deliver great investment results.”&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;NZ Super Fund Head of External Investments and Partnerships Del Hart says its investment in Fund 5 highlights its continued commitment to identifying commercially attractive opportunities to invest in New Zealand.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“This investment will help support the growth of local technology businesses that are high growth, typically internationally focused and will benefit from the management expertise and connections that come from an experienced and successful fund manager like Movac. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“Fund 5 is our second investment with Movac, following a $50m investment in Fund 4 in 2016 and, along with mandates with other local investment managers, represents an efficient way for the Fund to gain access to growth opportunities in small-medium sized New Zealand growth businesses.” &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;New Zealand Growth Capital Partners Investment Director James Pinner said the significant investments from institutional investors demonstrate that New Zealand venture capital is a viable and investable asset class. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“The hope is that other institutional investors – and other KiwiSaver funds in particular – will meaningfully invest in this asset class. What is also pleasing is the level of private investment being raised. The government’s requirement for the Elevate NZ Venture Fund is that it must invest alongside at least matching private capital. Elevate’s initial $10 million has been matched by $150 million of private capital and we expect there to be ratio of over seven times as much private capital as our investment at the Fund’s final close.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Venture capital firm Movac has secured investment from Kiwi Invest for the Kiwi Wealth KiwiSaver Scheme to become a cornerstone investor in the new Movac Fund 5 technology fund. It marks the first time an institutional player within the KiwiSaver space has entered the growth and venture capital ecosystem at this scale. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Movac Fund 5 is a $200-$250m growth capital fund which has a specific New Zealand focus and will invest over time in technology start-ups and growth companies. Its design allows it to support early stage companies as they grow, with capital available for later funding rounds, as well as investing in later-stage companies. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Kiwi Invest is the investment manager for the Kiwi Wealth KiwiSaver Scheme and has committed up to $54m in capital over the lifetime of the Fund. It joins contributions from NZ Super Fund ($70m), NZ Growth Capital Partners (up to $30m), with the balance from experienced entrepreneurs, family offices, individual investors, and several iwi. First close of Fund 5 will be September 23, and second close on 23 October.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Founded in 1998, Movac is a well-established and resourced venture capital firm in the technology sector and was selected by Kiwi Invest after a thorough due diligence process. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Simon O’Grady, Chief Investment Officer, Kiwi Invest, says, “Kiwi Invest views this as an important first step towards a potential series of private equity investments and the beginning of a pipeline of work over the coming years to build out this asset class. Kiwi Invest may look to build and diversify in this sector, based on the manager, geography and asset type from an investment perspective.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“Movac has a talented and experienced investment team, sound and well-tested processes, and a strong track record in supporting successful New Zealand tech start-ups and growth companies, helping them to grow their businesses globally.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“The market is changing and those providing capital are having to venture more into the private, unlisted sector on behalf of those seeking returns on investment. Kiwi Invest saw that it was the right time, with the right manager, and in the right sector for this investment.” &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The investment will be staggered over time as Movac goes through the process of selecting companies for funding and working directly to move them through the growth stages. Fund 5 is focused on backing this process in a graduated way, supported by thorough due diligence by all parties.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;The longer-term nature of the investment is consistent with the Kiwi Wealth KiwiSaver Scheme’s function as a long-term savings vehicle. It offers an opportunity for returns while remaining a small proportion of the diversified growth assets in the Scheme.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Phil McCaw, Managing Partner at Movac, says, “We are pleased to have successfully raised Movac Fund 5, and delighted to have Kiwi Invest on-board as a cornerstone investor – this is also the introduction of Kiwi Invest to venture capital investment.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“I’m delighted to have the support of Kiwi Invest as a cornerstone investor in Movac Fund 5. For many years I’ve been a vocal proponent of KiwiSaver managers allocating a small portion of their funds to the New Zealand venture capital sector. Not only has there been the potential for exceptional returns as we’ve experienced to date, but it’s also where fantastic innovation and job creation occurs. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“It is great to have a major KiwiSaver investment manager in the growth and venture capital ecosystem supporting the rapid expansion of local businesses. This long-term alignment is innovative and shows leadership and a new maturity in New Zealand tech and the investment sector. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“I congratulate the Kiwi Invest team for showing true market leadership in the sector with their significant investment in a venture capital fund like Movac Fund 5, and we look forward to working hard on their behalf to deliver great investment results.”&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;NZ Super Fund Head of External Investments and Partnerships Del Hart says its investment in Fund 5 highlights its continued commitment to identifying commercially attractive opportunities to invest in New Zealand.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“This investment will help support the growth of local technology businesses that are high growth, typically internationally focused and will benefit from the management expertise and connections that come from an experienced and successful fund manager like Movac. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“Fund 5 is our second investment with Movac, following a $50m investment in Fund 4 in 2016 and, along with mandates with other local investment managers, represents an efficient way for the Fund to gain access to growth opportunities in small-medium sized New Zealand growth businesses.” &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;New Zealand Growth Capital Partners Investment Director James Pinner said the significant investments from institutional investors demonstrate that New Zealand venture capital is a viable and investable asset class. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;“The hope is that other institutional investors – and other KiwiSaver funds in particular – will meaningfully invest in this asset class. What is also pleasing is the level of private investment being raised. The government’s requirement for the Elevate NZ Venture Fund is that it must invest alongside at least matching private capital. Elevate’s initial $10 million has been matched by $150 million of private capital and we expect there to be ratio of over seven times as much private capital as our investment at the Fund’s final close.”&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Kiwi Invest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;An investment approach that serves no goals but yours. New Zealand’s smart money grows here. Get tailored investment advice from a local team with a global focus, with $7.4 billion under management (as at 31 August 2020).&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;At Kiwi Invest, we offer significant private and wholesale investors a personal investment service - defined by a more global and objective focus to investment decisions and a track record of long-term performance through a broad range of market conditions. Kiwi Invest is also the investment team behind all of Kiwi Wealth’s funds.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Kiwi Invest is part of the Kiwi Group, owned by NZ Super Fund, New Zealand Post and ACC but operate completely independently.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;Our culture is based on true guardianship built on putting clients first and transparency. We take Responsible Investment seriously, applying RI principles across all our funds.&lt;br&gt;Because as Kiwis, we know that doing the right thing, is the smart thing too.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Movac&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1998, Movac is New Zealand's most experienced and successful venture capital firm, providing support to foster Kiwi founders and accelerate the growth of their tech businesses. Current portfolio companies include Aroa Biosurgery, Author-it, Vend, Unleashed Software, Parking Sense, Timely, Coretex, Mobi2Go, Revolution Fibres and TracPlus. Past portfolio companies include PowerbyProxi, Trade Me, eBus, Givealittle, and GreenButton.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Movac Fund 5 LP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Movac Fund 5 is a $200-$250m growth and venture capital fund that will invest in a broad portfolio of 20-25 New Zealand technology companies, diversified by stage and sector, ranging from across the spectrum from pre-revenue/pre-Series A, to Series A and Series B.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About NZ Super Fund&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The New Zealand Superannuation Fund invests money on behalf of the New Zealand Government to help pay for the increased cost of universal pension entitlements in the future. By doing this the Fund adds to Crown wealth, improves the ability of future Governments to pay for universal pensions, and ultimately reduces the tax burden on future New Zealanders. A long-term, growth-oriented investor, the Fund has around NZ$48 billion in assets, including more than $6 billion invested in New Zealand. The Fund is managed by a Crown entity, the Guardians of New Zealand Superannuation.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About NZGCP &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;Was established by the Government to build a vibrant early-stage investment, it manages the Elevate NZ Venture Fund - a $300m fund of funds program which looks to fill the capital gap for high growth New Zealand businesses at the Series A and B fund raising stage. Elevate’s objectives are to stimulate a functioning venture capital industry and make sure that high-growth New Zealand businesses have access to the capital and connections that they need in order to be successful. &lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;img src="https://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=703880&amp;amp;k=14&amp;amp;r=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.kiwiinvest.co.nz%2Finvestment-insights%2Fkiwi-invest-secures-movac-investment&amp;amp;bu=https%253A%252F%252Fwww.kiwiinvest.co.nz%252Finvestment-insights&amp;amp;bvt=rss" alt="" width="1" height="1" style="min-height:1px!important;width:1px!important;border-width:0!important;margin-top:0!important;margin-bottom:0!important;margin-right:0!important;margin-left:0!important;padding-top:0!important;padding-bottom:0!important;padding-right:0!important;padding-left:0!important; "&gt;</content:encoded>
      <category>(Our Updates) Latest News</category>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 00:08:12 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/kiwi-invest-secures-movac-investment</guid>
      <dc:date>2020-09-24T00:08:12Z</dc:date>
      <dc:creator>Contributor</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investment Update August 2020</title>
      <link>https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/market-update-august-2020</link>
      <description>&lt;div class="hs-featured-image-wrapper"&gt; 
 &lt;a href="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/market-update-august-2020" title="" class="hs-featured-image-link"&gt; &lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hubfs/Kiwi%20Investment%20Management/Monthly%20update%20%28Missive%29/GlobalMarketUpdate-JulyAug-1200px.png" alt="Investment Update August 2020" class="hs-featured-image" style="width:auto !important; max-width:50%; float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;"&gt; &lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;    
&lt;h2&gt;Global Market View&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Equity markets continued their steady climb with many global markets reaching all-time highs. The currency hedged MSCI All Country index returned 5.7% for the month. Economic data overseas showed signs of improvement, although much of it driven by massive government support.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;h2&gt;Global Market View&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Equity markets continued their steady climb with many global markets reaching all-time highs. The currency hedged MSCI All Country index returned 5.7% for the month. Economic data overseas showed signs of improvement, although much of it driven by massive government support.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;US markets were buoyed by signs that the latest cycle of Covid-19 numbers may be peaking and is looking past the threat of any worsening, as the US heads into winter and the flu season rolls around. Some of the positive market sentiment came on the back of growing optimism around a vaccine, although the efficacy and practicalities of distribution remain very much uncertain.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Economic data in the US exceeded expectations, with the housing market benefiting from record low mortgage rates and employment numbers gradually improving. Democrats and Republicans remain far apart on approving the next round of fiscal stimulus. The stalemate was exacerbated when President Trump issued an Executive Order in an attempt to circumvent Congress. The US market continues to rally despite the political gridlock, with the S&amp;amp;P 500 posting its best August since 1986, up 7.0%. Equities were driven higher by the soaring value of tech-related companies, as well as a very accommodative interest rate environment.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;In late August at the Jackson Hole Economic Symposium, the US Federal Reserve Chair Jerome Powell doubled down on the Fed’s dovish position. The Fed Chair announced a shift away from pre-emptively raising interest rates to combat higher expected inflation. This move would allow the Fed to let inflation run moderately above 2% for a period of time, thus signalling that interest rates would stay low for the foreseeable future. Powell also stated they would factor in the level of employment and not take steps to cool the labour market “unless there is clear evidence of inflationary pressure”.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;New Zealand equity markets rebounded from pressure brought about by the level 3 lockdown of Auckland. The local share market also battled through numerous shutdowns as a result of cyber-attacks on the NZX website to finish at an all-time high on 28 August, before losing some ground on concerns over the strengthening NZD. The NZD strengthened over the month following an initial dip as the RBNZ boosted the existing quantitative easing program from NZ$60 billion to NZ$100 billion and indicated that more preparation was in progress for negative interest rates.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hs-fs/hubfs/GlobalMarketUpdate-AugSept-1200px.png?width=796&amp;amp;name=GlobalMarketUpdate-AugSept-1200px.png" alt="GlobalMarketUpdate-AugSept-1200px" width="796" style="background-color: transparent; width: 796px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="#growth-performance"&gt;Growth Performance&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; |&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="#growth-positioning"&gt;Growth Positioning&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; |&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="#fixed-interest-performance"&gt;Fixed Interest Performance&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp; |&amp;nbsp;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="#fixed-interest-positioning"&gt;Fixed Interest Positioning&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;h2&gt;Growth&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://cdn2.hubspot.net/hub/703880/hubfs/Steffan-3.png?width=90&amp;amp;name=Steffan-3.png" alt="Steffan-3" width="90"&gt;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; &lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hs-fs/hubfs/nathan-field.png?width=90&amp;amp;name=nathan-field.png" alt="nathan-field" width="90" style="background-color: transparent; width: 90px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;by Steffan Berridge, Head of Quantitative Strategy &amp;amp; Nathan Field, Portfolio Manager - Global Thematic&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;h3&gt;Performance&lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The Kiwi Wealth Growth Fund (Growth PIE) returned 4.28% after tax and fees in August, 0.68% behind the MSCI All Country benchmark. The Global Thematic and Global Quantitative strategies contributed negatively to relative performance this month, while Core Global outperformed. The Kiwi dollar strengthened against the US greenback further which was a headwind for returns in foreign currency.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;Global Thematic was behind the benchmark in August although the absolute return was still a healthy 3.86%. Defensive themes such as snack foods and essential utilities dragged on performance relative to benchmark as the market rushed towards high flying stocks, where we are growing more cautious. Our best performing themes were athleisure and US home construction which both benefitted from optimism around consumer spending.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The Global Quantitative fund returned 3.87% in August, 0.76% behind the MSCI AC benchmark in yet another big month for large cap growth stocks. The market rally is still largely driven by TINA (There Is No Alternative to equities), as central banks reaffirmed their commitment to keep interest rates low. However, some aspects of the market point to lower quality gains, particularly the amount of retail money entering the market through online platforms, the positive impact of two high profile stock splits (&lt;strong&gt;Tesla, Apple&lt;/strong&gt;) and the narrowness of the market leadership. Energy was our best sector for the month with our underweight to the sector and a good month for Canadian infrastructure company &lt;strong&gt;Keyera&lt;/strong&gt; proving beneficial. However, this was outweighed by underperformance in the Technology and Discretionary sectors where we did not sufficiently capture the narrow list of names that outperformed for the month (particularly &lt;strong&gt;Salesforce.com&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Tesla&lt;/strong&gt;). Our Asian Technology holdings also gave back some of their recent strong gains (&lt;strong&gt;MediaTek, Samsung&lt;/strong&gt;).&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;h3&gt;Positioning&lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;In Global Thematic we are maintaining a defensive bias as we are increasingly wary of herd mentality driving some of the market’s leading stocks. As a result, we have reduced our weighting to recent outperformers in the technology and consumer discretionary sectors. We may lag the market in big return month’s like August, but we believe preserving the healthy gains already made this year is of paramount importance given the many uncertainties facing financial markets over coming months.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;For Global Quantitative, our top-down positioning targets higher quality sectors more suited to the current environment like Technology and increasingly Industrials. Stock selection favours companies with attractive metrics across earnings quality, capital efficiency, valuations, sentiment and sustainability. Over the month, we’ve increased our allocation to Technology (&lt;strong&gt;Visa, Mastercard, Trend Micro&lt;/strong&gt;) while trimming Financials (&lt;strong&gt;Bank of America, QBE Insurance&lt;/strong&gt;). Discretionary, Industrials, Technology and Healthcare are in favour, while Energy and Financials remain out of favour.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;h2&gt;Fixed Interest&lt;/h2&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hs-fs/hubfs/1.Website_Images/01._Homepage/Profiles/Carousel/Greg.png?width=90&amp;amp;name=Greg.png" alt="Greg" width="90" style="width: 90px; float: left; margin: 0px 10px 10px 0px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;by Greg Hayton, Head of Fixed Interest&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;h3&gt;Performance&lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The Kiwi Wealth Fixed Interest Fund (Fixed Interest PIE) returned 0.56% after fees and taxes in August slightly outperforming its benchmark. The outperformance can mostly be attributed to corporate and semi government bonds spreads (extra yield a non-government issuer pays versus a government bond) tightening relative to NZ Government Bonds over the month.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;The RBNZ’s release of their monetary policy statement on August 12th was the main event last month, by that it had the largest impact on the New Zealand bond market and subsequently our performance. The RBNZ’s Monetary Policy Statement was much more dovish than the market was expecting.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; The RBNZ stated “there is downside risk to our baseline economic scenario” citing in the statement the long-term concerns around tourism and migration. As a result of this forecast, they firstly announced that their QE bond buy-back programme known as LSAP (Large Scale Asset Purchases) for government bonds would be increased to $100 billion from $60 billion and they would increase the percentage limit of outstanding government bonds they can buy to 60% from 50% by June 2022. The RBNZ also talked up the prospect of taking the Official Cash Rate (OCR) to a negative interest rate next year coupled with commencing a Funding for Lending Programme for commercial banks. This facility would allow the RBNZ to lend to banks at the OCR (or thereabouts), which would provide cheap funds and allow banks to make cheaper loans (mortgages etc) to their customers. All of this means interest rates are going to be lower for longer and risks to further OCR rate cuts remain. It is clear from the RBNZ’s statement that they are going to err on the side of caution, and they will not be afraid to use more tools to meet their dual inflation and employment mandate. It is also interesting to note that the decision to up their QE programme was not influenced by the outbreak of COVID-19 in Auckland. The letter from the Minister of Finance approving the increase to 60% on behalf of the Crown was dated August 6&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, before the latest outbreak was known.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;a&gt;&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;h3&gt;Positioning&lt;/h3&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;It is fair to say the NZ economy has held up well post the level 4 lockdown, performing much better than what most economists predicted. Areas such as primary industries where commodity prices have held up and the housing market, which has benefitted from lower interest rates have exceeded economist’s expectations. Concerns still exist however, as economists worry that the unemployment rate has been artificially held down by the wage subsidy scheme and that we could still see an unemployment rate of around 10%, as the effects of the scheme wear off. It seems that hospitality and tourism jobs, which generally pay a lower wage and have a higher proportion of young workers are going to be the most affected by the COVID-19 recession.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;In global news the annual Federal Reserve monetary policy symposium was held. Chair of the Federal Reserve, Jerome Powell stated that the Fed was now adapting their policy to allow inflation to run at a higher rate than previously stated before they would look to tighten monetary policy. This statement caused long term global interest rates to move higher, as all things being equal this would increase the probability that inflation will run at a higher rate in the future. The impact on the New Zealand Government Bond market was rather muted however, as the RBNZs policy of buying NZ Government Bonds across all maturities kept longer dated bond yields suppressed.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;We continued to focus on high quality credits over August, as we continue to be very selective about the types of names and companies we want to own. We added to &lt;strong&gt;Transpower &lt;/strong&gt;(AA-), &lt;strong&gt;Local Government Authority bonds (LGFA)&lt;/strong&gt; (AA+), &lt;strong&gt;Rentenbank&lt;/strong&gt; (AAA), &lt;strong&gt;International Finance Corporation&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;(IFC)&lt;/strong&gt; (AAA) and &lt;strong&gt;New Zealand Government bonds&lt;/strong&gt; (AA+).&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="text-align: justify;"&gt;We increased the average maturity within the fund over the month by about a quarter of a year, as it became increasingly clear that the RBNZ was going to keep interest rates very low for a longer period. From their actions above to not only indicate that they are seriously looking to drop the Official Cash Rate (OCR) into negative territory but to also couple that with a major augmentation of their LSAP programme meant that the probability that interest rates were going to be even lower over the near term was amplified. We have the most conviction at the moment that short to intermediate term interest rates (out to 7 years) will remain low and have therefore over weighted the portfolio to these maturities.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;img src="https://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=703880&amp;amp;k=14&amp;amp;r=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.kiwiinvest.co.nz%2Finvestment-insights%2Fmarket-update-august-2020&amp;amp;bu=https%253A%252F%252Fwww.kiwiinvest.co.nz%252Finvestment-insights&amp;amp;bvt=rss" alt="" width="1" height="1" style="min-height:1px!important;width:1px!important;border-width:0!important;margin-top:0!important;margin-bottom:0!important;margin-right:0!important;margin-left:0!important;padding-top:0!important;padding-bottom:0!important;padding-right:0!important;padding-left:0!important; "&gt;</content:encoded>
      <category>(Our Updates) Market Updates</category>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 02:43:30 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>frank.braden@kiwiwealth.co.nz (Frank Braden)</author>
      <guid>https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/market-update-august-2020</guid>
      <dc:date>2020-09-07T02:43:30Z</dc:date>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kiwi Invest scores A+ for strategy and governance in first PRI Assessment</title>
      <link>https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/green-washing-undermines-true-responsible-investment</link>
      <description>&lt;div class="hs-featured-image-wrapper"&gt; 
 &lt;a href="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/green-washing-undermines-true-responsible-investment" title="" class="hs-featured-image-link"&gt; &lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hubfs/Kiwi-Invest-Mossgreen-Tag-CMYK.jpg" alt="kiwi-invest-logo" class="hs-featured-image" style="width:auto !important; max-width:50%; float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;"&gt; &lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;    
&lt;p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 0in; padding-left: 0in;"&gt;Kiwi Invest has come away with an A+ rating for Strategy and Governance in its first assessment from the PRI (Principles for Responsible Investment), after becoming a signatory to the global responsible investor initiative in February 2020.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 0in; padding-left: 0in;"&gt;Kiwi Invest has come away with an A+ rating for Strategy and Governance in its first assessment from the PRI (Principles for Responsible Investment), after becoming a signatory to the global responsible investor initiative in February 2020.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 0in; padding-left: 0in;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 0in; padding-left: 0in;"&gt;PRI, the world’s leading proponent of responsible investment, partners with the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.unepfi.org/"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;UN Environment Programme Finance Initiative&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.unglobalcompact.org/"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration: none;"&gt;UN Global Compact&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to advance responsible investment practices and is the international benchmark for how institutional investors should manage environmental, social and governance (ESG) issues. The PRI will continue to monitor and independently rate Kiwi Invest’s performance against RI standards in its investment processes, which also includes its proactive engagement with the companies it invests in to encourage continuous improvements to ESG policies.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 0in; padding-left: 0in;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 0in; padding-left: 0in;"&gt;Steffan Berridge, quantitative and responsible investments strategist for Kiwi Invest, says, “&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt;We’re delighted to have become a PRI signatory this year and gone ahead with submitting a full transparency report even though this is not compulsory in the first year. The scores have given us a validation of our strong responsible investment credentials in key areas we’ve been developing, and a benchmark to improve on in others.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 0in; padding-left: 0in;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 0in; padding-left: 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt;“We’re continuing to observe the practice of green washing in the fund management industry. While some of us are using responsible investment activities to push for concrete progress on key ESG issues, others unfortunately are merely pandering to RI and using it as a marketing ploy. Some fund managers exercise very little control over their investments and the companies they’re invested in – or simply have a token ESG or ‘impact fund’ – and investors are left in the dark. To this end, &lt;/span&gt;we’re pleased the Financial Markets Authority is now setting expectations that fund managers who are promoting funds as ‘green’ or using ESG principles are doing what they say.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 0in; padding-left: 0in;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 0in; padding-left: 0in;"&gt;“Investors deserve to know precisely how a responsible investing strategy is being implemented on their behalf, which companies their money is invested in and how ESG criteria are being applied. We think it should be mandatory for fund managers to disclose investment exclusions and shareholder proxy voting records on all funds marketed as responsible. These principles are why global benchmarks such as PRI are so important, and why Kiwi Invest became a signatory."&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 0in; padding-left: 0in;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 0in; padding-left: 0in;"&gt;Kiwi Invest is the investment team behind Kiwi Wealth’s funds; it implements exclusion, integration and engagement strategies across all funds it manages. All of Kiwi Wealth’s KiwiSaver funds are independently certified by the Responsible Investment Association of Australasia (RIAA) and information on sector, company exclusions and proxy voting records are always publicly available to investors.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 0in; padding-left: 0in;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 0in; padding-left: 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt;Kiwi&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt;Invest’s &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt;2017 white paper on responsible investment, endorsed by the Responsible Investment Association Australasia, found that responsible investing objectives were best achieved when ESG factors were considered across all investments in a portfolio in combination with actively engaging with companies and exercising proxy voting rights to influence company performance. The white paper, ‘Investing in an imperfect world: Our take on true responsible investment’, can be accessed&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.kiwiwealth.co.nz/ri-whitepaper?__hstc=156076260.8e19c0ac91b5fc2818ff0cc11ad47c16.1597975027899.1597975027899.1597975027899.1&amp;amp;__hssc=156076260.1.1597975027900&amp;amp;__hsfp=3051137587"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration: none; background-color: white;"&gt;here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 0in; padding-left: 0in;"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p style="margin-top: 0in; margin-right: 0in; margin-bottom: 0in; padding-left: 0in;"&gt;&lt;span style="background-color: white;"&gt;Find out more about Kiwi our approach to&lt;/span&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/our-difference/responsible-investment-policy"&gt;responsible investment. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;img src="https://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=703880&amp;amp;k=14&amp;amp;r=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.kiwiinvest.co.nz%2Finvestment-insights%2Fgreen-washing-undermines-true-responsible-investment&amp;amp;bu=https%253A%252F%252Fwww.kiwiinvest.co.nz%252Finvestment-insights&amp;amp;bvt=rss" alt="" width="1" height="1" style="min-height:1px!important;width:1px!important;border-width:0!important;margin-top:0!important;margin-bottom:0!important;margin-right:0!important;margin-left:0!important;padding-top:0!important;padding-bottom:0!important;padding-right:0!important;padding-left:0!important; "&gt;</content:encoded>
      <category>(Our Updates) Latest News</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 21:30:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/green-washing-undermines-true-responsible-investment</guid>
      <dc:date>2020-09-01T21:30:00Z</dc:date>
      <dc:creator>Kiwi Invest</dc:creator>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>RBNZ outlook remains dovish.</title>
      <link>https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/rbnz-outlook-remains-dovish</link>
      <description>&lt;div class="hs-featured-image-wrapper"&gt; 
 &lt;a href="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/rbnz-outlook-remains-dovish" title="" class="hs-featured-image-link"&gt; &lt;img src="https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/hubfs/BinocularDollars.jpg" alt="lady with binoculars with dollars over lenses" class="hs-featured-image" style="width:auto !important; max-width:50%; float:left; margin:0 15px 15px 0;"&gt; &lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;/div&gt;    
&lt;p&gt;The RBNZ’s Monetary Policy Statement released last Wednesday was much more dovish than the market was expecting. The RBNZ stated “there is downside risk to our baseline economic scenario” citing in the statement the long-term concerns around tourism and migration.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The RBNZ’s Monetary Policy Statement released last Wednesday was much more dovish than the market was expecting. The RBNZ stated “there is downside risk to our baseline economic scenario” citing in the statement the long-term concerns around tourism and migration.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;p&gt;As a result of this forecast, they firstly announced that their QE bond buy-back programme known as LSAP (Large Scale Asset Purchases) for government bonds would be increased to $100 billion from $60 billion and they would increase the percentage limit of outstanding government bonds they can buy to 60% from 50% by June 2022.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;The RBNZ also talked up the prospect of taking the OCR to a negative interest rate next year coupled with commencing a Funding for Lending Programme for commercial banks.  This facility would allow the RBNZ to lend to banks at the Official Cash Rate (OCR) rate (or thereabouts), which would provide cheap funds and allow banks to make cheaper loans (mortgages etc) to their customers.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;All of this means interest rates are going to be lower for longer and risks to further OCR rate cuts remain. It is clear from the RBNZ’s statement that they are going to err on the side of caution, and they will not be afraid to use more tools to meet their dual inflation and employment mandate.&lt;/p&gt; 
&lt;p&gt;It is also interesting to note that the decision to up their QE programme was not influenced by the outbreak of COVID-19 in Auckland last week. The letter from the Minister of Finance approving the increase to 60% on behalf of the Crown was dated August 6th.&lt;/p&gt;  
&lt;img src="https://track.hubspot.com/__ptq.gif?a=703880&amp;amp;k=14&amp;amp;r=https%3A%2F%2Fwww.kiwiinvest.co.nz%2Finvestment-insights%2Frbnz-outlook-remains-dovish&amp;amp;bu=https%253A%252F%252Fwww.kiwiinvest.co.nz%252Finvestment-insights&amp;amp;bvt=rss" alt="" width="1" height="1" style="min-height:1px!important;width:1px!important;border-width:0!important;margin-top:0!important;margin-bottom:0!important;margin-right:0!important;margin-left:0!important;padding-top:0!important;padding-bottom:0!important;padding-right:0!important;padding-left:0!important; "&gt;</content:encoded>
      <category>(Our Updates) Latest News</category>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 03:36:41 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>greg.hayton@kiwiwealth.co.nz (Greg Hayton)</author>
      <guid>https://www.kiwiinvest.co.nz/investment-insights/rbnz-outlook-remains-dovish</guid>
      <dc:date>2020-08-18T03:36:41Z</dc:date>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
